In this video we will write the same program from the previous part, just in a different language.
在这段视频中，我们将编写相同的程序，使用不同的编程语言：
The C program got compiled by a compiler in machine code that can be executed directly.
由编译器编译的 C 程序，是可以直接执行的机器代码。
Python on the other hand is an interpreted language.
Python不同，是一个解释语言。
To understand the difference I try to make an abstract example.
为了便于理解，我试图做一个抽象的例子。
You can imagine a program written in C as a machine built for a very specific task.
你可以把用 C编写的程序 ，想象成为一项特殊任务，而制造的机器。
And python itself is such a machine written in C. But it’s a special machine ... a robot,
而Python本身就是这样一个机器，但却是一台特殊的机器… 一台机器人，
which is built to interpret different language of code - python code.
它用来解释，不同的语言代码 - python代码。
So in a trivialized sense, somebody wrote C code in a file “python.c”.
所以，如同有人，在一个"python.c"文件中，编写 C 代码。
Then used gcc like in the previous video to compile this sourcecode into a binary with
然后，像之前视频使用的 "gcc" 一样，将此源代码，编译为一个二进制文件
the name python.
名字叫做：python。
You can see that when you use the tool “file” to display file information.
当，使用显示文件信息的工具"file"时，您可以看到这一点。
When you use file on our c matrix program, it says it’s an ELF executable.
当对我们的 "matrix" C 程序，使用 "file" 时，它说，该程序是一个 ELF 可执行文件。
And when you do the same for the python program it also says that it is an ELF executable.
当你对生出的"python"程序，做同样的操作时，它同样表示，该程序是一个 ELF 可执行文件。
Now when you execute the “python” program, you get an interpreter prompt, where you can
现在，当您执行"python"程序时，你会得到一个解释提示">>> "，
enter text and python will interpret it for you.
在这里，你可以输入文本，而 "python" 将解释它。
Or just pass it a python script file and it will execute it.
或者是，传递一个 python 脚本文件，也能够执行。
I hope that makes sense.
我希望，这是讲得明白。
So let’s create a new python script called matrix.py.
那么，让我们创建一个新的 python脚本，"matrix.py"。
We will also open our previous code alongside,to compare them.
我们还会在旁边，打开以前的代码文件，比较一下它们。
We can do that with vim by specifying both filenames with minus capital O.
我们可以通过"-O"带文件名，同时指定两文件。
This tells vim to open the files split vertically.
这告诉 Vim，打开垂直拆分的文件布局。
Now check if the cursor is in the correct document.
现在检查光标，是否在正确的文件。
If not you can use CTRL+W Left or Right to switch between the views.
如果没有，可以使用 "ctrl+w"加上左或右箭头，在视图之间切换。
Now enter the insert mode by pressing i and let’s get started.
现在，按 "i"，进入插入模式我们开始吧。
In python we don’t have to specify a main function.
在 python 中，我们不必指定 "main" 函数。
The code will be just executed sequentially from the start of the file to the end.
代码将按顺序执行，从文件的开头到结尾。
To access the command-line arguments argv we have to import a python module called sys.
访问命令行参数"argv"，我们必须导入一个名为 "sys" 的 python模块。
With print sys.argv we can print the content of this variable.
使用"print sys.argv"，我们可以打印这个变量的内容。
So let’s see how this sys.argv variable looks like.
那么，让我们看看这个"sys.argv"变量是怎么样的。
First save the file with esc, colon, w.
首先用"esc"、":w"，保存文件。
Then you can use colon ! to execute a command.
然后你可以用 ":!" 去执行(终端)命令。
For example ls.
例如 "ls"。
You will see that the editor disappeared into the background and it displays the result
你会看到，编辑画面消失在背景，然后
of the ls command.
显示 "ls" 命令结果。
So let’s use that to execute our python program.
所以，让我们用它来执行我们的 python 程序。
Go back by pressing Enter.
按回车键，返回。
Colon ! python to start python and as first argument we specify the script name which
":! python" 启动 python，其跟着的第一个参数，我们指定脚本名
is matrix.py.
是 "matrix.py"。
Instead of writing the name you can also just use %. Vim will automatically replace the
除了，写名字，你还可以使用"%"。Vim会将"%"
% with the current filename.
自动更换为当前文件名。
You can now see that the first argument was matrix.py.
你现在可以看到第一个参数是"matrix.py"。
And that’s all we got.
这就是我们所做的一切
Like I explained in the last video, the arguments passed to the program start with the programs
就像，我在上一个视频中，解释的那样，程序名后面，开始传递的，就是程序的
filename.
参数。
Now let’s add a few arbitrary arguments.
现在，让我们添加一些任意参数。
A normal one, one with quotes and spaces and some more words.
一个普通的，有引号和空格的，还有多些字。
Maybe even with more spaces in between, to just see what happens.
甚至在中间有更多的空格，看看会发生什么。
There is the output.
有输出。
So the brackets indicate a list in python. and the elements are comma separated.
所以，方括号"[]"，代表 python 中的一个列表。其中的元素用逗号分隔。
And the list contains many strings starting with the filename and the stuff we placed
这个列表中，包含许多字符串，有开始的文件名，和
afterwards.
之后我们放的东西。
Hope that makes command-line arguments a bit more clearer.
希望，能让命令行参数更清楚。
Ok so to check if we have got two arguments, we don’t need a counter of arguments like
OK，为了检查我们是否有两个参数，我们不需要
argc.
"argc" 那样的
We can just check if len(sys.argv)==2.
我们可以用"if len(sys.argv)==2"检查。
Note that python doesn’t use curly braces to define context.
注意 python 不使用大括号"{}"，定义作用域。
We have to use indentation… urgh.
我们得用缩进… 呃。
When I press TAB I get tabs.
当我按下 tab键 时，我会得到 tab（2/4个空格合并的大小）。
That’s ugly.
但这太难看了。
I prefer everything to be filled with simple spaces.
我喜欢一切，都用简单的空格。
So you can use set expandtab shiftwidth=4 softtabstop=4.
所以，可以使用"set expandtab shiftwidth=4 softtabstop=4"。
Now we get 4 spaces when tab is pressed.
现在，当按下 tab键 时，我们得到 4个空格。
Now we wan’t to print the first argument.
现在，我们不想打印第一个参数。
So with print and pythons special format string syntax we can do exactly the same like in
所以，有了 "print" 和 Python 特殊格式字符串语法，我们可以像 C 一样。
C. Inside the string with curley braces we can define which following format parameter
在我们定义的花括号字符串中，决定格式参数接下来
shall be placed here.
所占的位置。
And we start counting with 0, so here will be the first format parameter.
我们从 0 开始计数，所以这里是第一个格式参数。
the sys module.
stderr(标准错误流)
So sys.stderr.write and the again Usage curley braces 0 to indicate here should be the first
所以，"sys.stderr.write"，和花括号中的"0"，此处应为第一个格式变量。
format variable. and the first format variable is the first element of the argv list.
第一个格式变量，正是 "argv"列表的第一个元素。
Note that the simple print doesn’t need the backslash n newline at the end.
请注意，简单的打印不需要，尾端加上"\n"换行符。
but the write needs it.
但"write"需要。
That’s because pythons says that printing with a newline at the end is pretty common,
那是因为 Python说: "print"函数要换行很常见，
so it does that automatically for print.
所以，它会自动打印出来。
but if you use a bit more low level access function, then we have to add it ourselves.
但是，如果你使用一点底层的访问函数，那我们必须自己添加它。
Also that fact that we use “write” to output text should peak your curiosity.
同时，我们使用"write"来输出文本，应该引起了你的好奇。
Sounds like writing to a file?
听起来像是，在写(write)入文件？
Well.
Well。
Everything is a file as you may remember from the linux introduction video.
"一切都是文件"，正如 Linux简介那视频 所说。
So keep that in mind when we talk about this later.
所以，当我们谈论这个的时候。要记住这一点。
Ok done.
OK，好了。
Let’s test it.
让我们测试一下。
save it and quit vim.
保存，并退出Vim。
Make sure to quit two times for both open views.
确保打开的两个，都退出了视图。
Now python matrix.py works.
"python matrix.py"工作啦。
Just like our C program.
就像我们的 C程序 一样。
If you don’t want to type python before your python script all the time we can do
如果之前不想在你的 python脚本 之前，输入 python，
something about that.
关于这一点嘛。
Open the script again and create a new line above the import.
再次，打开脚本，并在"import"之上，创建新行
Remember how you can press o instead of i to enter insert mode, which creates a new
记住你是可以按 "o，而不是"i"进入插入模式，这将
empty line below your cursor?
在光标下，创建一个新的的空行？
Guess what happens when you use shift O.
猜猜当你使用"shift o"时，会发生什么。
It creates a new empty line above your cursor and enters insert mode.
它会在光标上方，创建一个新的空行，进入插入模式。
Now add shebang with the path to the python binary.
现在，添加二进制 python 的 "shebang"路径。
#!/usr/bin/python There is also a nice wikipedia entry about
"#!/usr/bin/python""Shebang"，还有一个不错的维基百科词条
shebang, so check that out.
可以看看。
This line tells the program loader that this is a script that should be executed with python.
这一行，告诉程序加载器，这是应该用Python执行的脚本。
So it basically does python matrix.py for us.
所以它基本上，帮我们做了"python matrix.py"
Now we can execute it like our C program, by using the path to the python script…
现在，我们可以像执行C程序一样执行它，就是，通过使用 python脚本的路径…
Why is that?
为什么会这样？
let’s have a look at the permissions.
让我们看看权限。
ls -la to display all files along with their permissions but also use matrix *. This basically
"ls-la"显示所有文件及其权限，但也使用"matrix*"。这基本上
means that it should display all files that start with matrix and anything can then follow.
意味着它应该显示，从"matrix"开始，后跟一切的文件。
When we compare our matrix binary with the matrix python script we notice that it has
当我们将 "matrix" 二进制与我们注意到，Matrix python脚本
a couple of x.
一对X。
X stands for executable.
X代表可执行文件。
But our file only has r and w, which stands for read and write permissions.
但是我们的档案只有R和W，代表用于读写权限。
So to be allowed to execute it, we have to add the execute permission to that file.
所以要被允许执行它，我们必须向该文件添加执行权限。
We can sue chmod for that, which stands for change mode bits of a file.
我们可以起诉希莫德，这代表更改文件的模式位。
Remember to always read the man page to learn more about the commands.
记住要经常阅读手册来学习有关命令的详细信息。
So we can use chmod +x to add execution rights and the filename.
所以我们可以使用chmod+x添加执行权限以及文件名。
When we now list the files we see that it now has execution permissions.
当我们现在列出文件时，我们看到它现在具有执行权限。
I mentioned this in the very first video briefly, but maybe now is a good moment to talk about
我在第一个视频中简单地提到了这一点，但也许现在是谈论的好时机
it a bit more.
再多一点。
Tab completion is extremely handy.
制表完成非常方便。
For example when I start typing the current path with dot slash.
例如，当我开始输入当前带点斜线的路径。
And hit tab twice, it shows me all possible files that could follow.
点击两次标签，它显示了所有可能的可以跟踪的文件。
So we want matrix.
所以我们要 "matrix" 。
Let’s just type one letter m and hit tab again.
我们只需输入一个字母M，然后点击标签再一次。
Now it will have automatically filled it in as matrix.
现在它会自动填写作为 "matrix" 。
Because there are multiple matrix files it has stopped at the part where they start to
因为有多个 "matrix" 文件停在他们开始的地方
differ.
不同。
Double Tab to display all options.
双选项卡显示所有选项。
Now add a . which makes the only option left matrix.py.
现在添加一个。这是唯一的选择MyRix.Py
Tab again and we got the whole filename.
又是tab，我们得到了整个文件名。
I use python a lot.
我经常用Python。
Almost anything I program I write in python.
几乎所有我用python编写的程序。
So most of my examples will be written in python and it’s also a language I highly
所以我的大部分例子都会写在而且它也是一种语言
recommend to learn in general.
建议一般学习。
So maybe checkout codecademy python courses or just google yourself.
所以也许可以结帐codecademy python课程或者自己搜索。
Before we finish, let’s keep our system updated.
在我们结束之前，让我们保持我们的系统更新。
Type sudo apt-get update, to update the package list from the repositories.
键入sudo apt get update，更新包从存储库中列出。
And the apt-get upgrade, to install new versions for software you have installed. ...
以及apt-get升级，以安装新版本对于已安装的软件。